JACLYN GUNTON

UX DESIGNER



PROFILE

I'm a UX designer with 4 years of digital design experience and a background in marketing communications and graphic design. I'm looking for a UX role where I can harness my creative mindset and experience in UX strategy and UI design to craft experiences that are relevant, inclusive, and meaningful to people.

- 647.239.0529
- in linkedin.com/in/jgunton
- ⊙ Toronto, ON
- **§** jaclyngunton.design

EDUCATION

CREATIVE ADVERTISING DIPLOMA

Seneca College | Toronto, ON 2014 - 2016

BACHELOR OF ARTS

Western University | London, ON 2010 - 2014

- Media, Information & Technoculture (major)
- Visual Arts (major)

SPECIALITIES

MOBILE & WEB APPS UI DESIGN
DESIGN THINKING LEAN UX

EXPERIENCE

MARKETING & DESIGN SPECIALIST

Sep 2016 - Apr 2019

MolecuLight Inc. | Toronto, ON

Sole in-house designer at a fast-paced healthtech startup, collaborating with a cross-functional, agile team to build an Android medical device product from end-to-end.

- Developed personas, customer journey maps, storyboards, and affinity maps to communicate research findings from user interviews, stakeholder interviews, and field research
- Acted as a user-advocate during the development process, subjecting early-stage designs to usability testing and offering implementation suggestions from a user-centred perspective
- Produced sketches, wireframes, and designed high-fidelity mockups and rapid prototypes using Axure, Sketch, and Invision
- Directed visual design of all new features and enhancements for the UI, involving software team early and often in the process to understand implementation challenges and design limitations
- Acted as the "go-to source" with in-depth knowledge of user interface best practices and standards
- Developed consistent design documentation that included all mockups, user interactions, copy, and design specs and assets for smooth design handoff to developers
- Presented key milestone deliverables and pitched designs to executive level stakeholders and synthesized their feedback in new design iterations
- Met with product manager and software team at weekly status meetings to discuss user requirements, key deliverables, and project deadlines to deliver designs on time and within budget

GRAPHIC DESIGNER (FREELANCE)

Feb 2017 - Mar 2017

SQL Power Group | Toronto, ON

6-week contract updating the visual brand identity for a software firm specialized in fully-integrated data collection, return management and analytics solutions for businesses.

- Consulted with CEO/founder and the marketing team to create cohesive designs that reflected the organization's business goals
- Produced relevant written and visual content for the company website and email campaigns to engage the target audience
- Managed revisions and approvals, artwork and information accuracy under tight timelines
- Created logos, icons, infographics, web banners, and style guides using Adobe InDesign, Illustrator, and Photoshop

JACLYN GUNTON

UX DESIGNER



CONTACT

647.239.0529

im linkedin.com/in/jgunton

WIREFRAMES

§ jaclyngunton.design

UX DESIGN SKILLS

UI DESIGN USER RESEARCH

RAPID PROTOTYPING PERSONAS

SKETCHING USER FLOWS

HTML/CSS (BASIC) IOS & ANDROID

USER TESTING

PROGRAMS & TOOLS

ADOBE XD SKETCH

ADOBE INDESIGN CRAFT

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR INVISION

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP AXURE

MS OFFICE SUITE FIGMA

WORDPRESS BALSAMIQ

JIRA KEYNOTE

EXPERIENCE continued

ART INSTRUCTOR

Jun 2016 - Feb 2017

Paint Nite | Toronto, ON

- Led as many as 50 people in step-by-step painting tutorial events around the city
- Created a friendly and upbeat atmosphere with music, drinks, and cheesy jokes to generate positive customer experiences

DESIGN INTERN

Feb 2014 - May 2014

Western University | London, ON

Completed a 4 month co-op for my university degree in the Communications & Publications department of Student Services.

- Developed content for web and print to engage the Western community and increase awareness of student services
- Created infographics and presentation decks that were visually appealing and on-brand using Illustrator and PowerPoint

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Sep 2017 - Present

Get REAL | Toronto, ON

Get REAL is a Canadian non-profit that combats LGBTQ+ discrimination and promotes acceptance in schools, summer camps, and workplaces across North America.

- Created original graphics and slogans for T-shirts and hoodies in collaboration with co-founders to be sold online to fund outreach programs and inclusivity workshops
- Participated in the launch of new collections, promoted new merchandise on Instagram and Facebook to generate advocacy

EMAIL MARKETING DESIGNER

Sep 2016 - Oct 2018

Start Proud | Toronto, ON

Start Proud is a non-profit that empowers members of the LGBTQ+ community to be Canada's leaders of tomorrow; where all institutions embrace diversity and inclusion in the workplace.

- Designed and deployed monthly email campaigns to 2500+ e-newsletter subscribers using Mailchimp
- Created custom e-newsletter templates in Mailchimp using basic HTML/CSS to design a look and feel that reflected the brand and resonated with the target audience
- Generated report summaries for marketing team and data analyst to evaluate areas of opportunity to grow the email list